Guide to the Stanford Family Scrapbooks SC0033F
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford family scrapbooks
1865-1894
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford family.
SC0033F
19 Linear Feet (37 volumes)
7 microfilm reel(s)
Family scrapbooks, compiled for the Stanford family. Subjects cover a wide range of family activities including railroad affairs, the Palo Alto Stock Farm, the Vina Ranch, the University, the United States Senate, politics, personal affairs of the Stanford's, and horses.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Stanford family and heirs.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Alternative Formats
Also available on microfilm in Stanford University Archives: Stanford, Calif.: Stanford University Libraries, 197-? 4 microfilm reels; 4 in ., 35 mm.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Leland Stanford was born March 9, 1824 in Watervliet Township, New York. He married Jane Lathrop in 1850 and on May 14, 1868, Jane and Leland's only child was born in Sacramento, California. Leland, Jr. died March 13, 1884 at the age of 15 years, 10 months. His early death inspired the founding of Leland Stanford, Jr. University by his parents. Leland, Sr. died June 21, 1893 and Jane died February 28, 1905.
Description of the Collection
Family scrapbooks, compiled for the Stanford family. Subjects cover a wide range of family activities including railroad affairs, the Palo Alto Stock Farm, the Vina Ranch, the University, the United States Senate, politics, personal affairs of the Stanford's, and horses.
Subject Index
Lathrop, Daniel - death B 87-88
Harrison law lectures D 76
Mausoleum D 77
Memorial Church, plans for D 71
Newton, Dr. 6 76
Religion at Stanford 3 4
Stanford, Asa Phillips 31 10, 45, 47
Stanford, Charles 31 2 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Biography (1892) 3 14, 129
Stanford, Jane L. - Charities 2 100, 108
Stanford, Jane L. - Charities 6 85, 87
Stanford, Jane L. - Charities 8 18-20
Stanford, Jane L. - Charities B 76-77, 80
Stanford, Jane L. - Charities C 11, 14
Stanford, Jane L. - Charities D 44
Stanford, Jane L. - Deed of Grant 20 2
Stanford, Jane L. - Deed of Grant C 1
Stanford, Jane L. - Death 31 10 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Estate 31 10 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Father Serra Monument 1 47
Stanford, Jane L. - Father Serra Monument 2 32 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Father Serra Monument 3 5
Stanford, Jane L. - Father Serra Monument 21 57
Stanford, Jane L. - Inheritance - tax law suit 24 1 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Jewels 3 91
Stanford, Jane L. - Jewels 2 24
Stanford, Jane L. - Jewels 14 35
Stanford, Jane L. - Jewels 18 43
Stanford, Jane L. - Jewels 23 31
Stanford, Jane L. - Jewels 31 10, 40, 48
Stanford, Jane L. - Jewels B 56
Stanford, Jane L. - Jewels D 16
Stanford, Jane L. - Kindergartens 1 21 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Kindergartens 2 11 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Kindergartens 3 33 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Kindergartens 8 15-17
Stanford, Jane L. - Kindergartens 14 30-33
Stanford, Jane L. - Kindergartens 17 32, 61, 99
Stanford, Jane L. - Kindergartens 18 40549
Stanford, Jane L. - Kindergartens 20 25
Stanford, Jane L. - Kindergartens 25 8
Stanford, Jane L. - Kindergartens B 77, 80, 84
Stanford, Jane L. - Kindergartens C 6 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Portraits B 55-56
Stanford, Jane L. - Religion 2 111
Stanford, Jane L. - Religion 21 22
Stanford, Jane L. - Social Life 1 13 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Social Life 2 2 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Social Life 3 2 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Social Life 11 49-50
Stanford, Jane L. - Social Life 14 39, 47
Stanford, Jane L. - Social Life 17 53 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Social Life 18 6-10, 40
Stanford, Jane L. - Social Life 20 38
Stanford, Jane L. - Social Life B 60 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Social Life D 41
Stanford, Jane L. - Travels 3 46 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - Travels 31 35-36
Stanford, Jane L. - Travels 32 1 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - and the University 3 91, 123
Stanford, Jane L. - and the University 13 33
Stanford, Jane L. - and the University 23 22-30
Stanford, Jane L. - and the University 31 36, 44
Stanford, Jane L. - and the University C 1 ff
Stanford, Jane L. - and the University 25 59
Stanford, Jane L. - and the Museum 3 39, 59, 131
Stanford, Jane L. - and the Museum 14 38-39
Stanford, Jane L. - and the Museum 23 26
Stanford, Jane L. - Washington, D.C. 3 4, 7, 47
Stanford, Jane L. - Washington, D.C. D 52, 65
Stanford, Jane L. - Will 31 39, 48
Stanford, Josiah [1817-1890] 1 81, 115
Stanford, Leland - Addresses 1 24, 56, 104
Stanford, Leland - Addresses 2 6 ff
Stanford, Leland - Addresses 3 152-155
Stanford, Leland - Addresses 6 39 ff
Stanford, Leland - Addresses 7 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Addresses 12 40546
Stanford, Leland - Addresses 17 6 ff
Stanford, Leland - Addresses 19 14-17
Stanford, Leland - Addresses 26 40734
Stanford, Leland - Appointed Regent State University B 59
Stanford, Leland - Biography 1 3 ff
Stanford, Leland - Biography 2 17
Stanford, Leland - Biography 3 11 ff
Stanford, Leland - Biography 6 74, 78
Stanford, Leland - Biography 9 175, 189
Stanford, Leland - Biography 12 40680
Stanford, Leland - Biography 14 14
Stanford, Leland - Biography 19 6
Stanford, Leland - Biography 20 3
Stanford, Leland - Biography 31 20 ff
Stanford, Leland - Biography B 11-12, 85
Stanford, Leland - Biography D 40555
Stanford, Leland - Brothers 14 37
Stanford, Leland - Brothers 20 30
Stanford, Leland - Brothers 31 2 ff
Stanford, Leland - Cartoons about 1 116, 162
Stanford, Leland - Cartoons about 2 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Cartoons about 3 159, 163
Stanford, Leland - Cartoons about 16 3 ff
Stanford, Leland - Cartoons about 19 2 ff
Stanford, Leland - Cartoons about B 9
Stanford, Leland - Cartoons about D 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1861-1872 B 3 ff
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1865 A 33604
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1871-78 28 3-135
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1872 26 5 ff
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1872 29 1-198
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1872-73 30 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1873 27 2 ff
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1872-1875 7 7 ff
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1881 6 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1885-1889 11 32
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1885-1889 18 25-32, 71
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1887-1891 17 6 ff
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1888 19 3 ff
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1890 21 1
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1892 3 67 ff
Stanford, Leland - Central Pacific 1894 24 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Chinese 6 71
Stanford, Leland - Charities 3 93, 128
Stanford, Leland - Charities 6 42, 86
Stanford, Leland - Death 3 138 ff
Stanford, Leland - Death 4 3-115
Stanford, Leland - Death 5 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Death 9 132 ff
Stanford, Leland - Death 10 60 ff
Stanford, Leland - Death 13 52 ff
Stanford, Leland - Death D 1-12, 14 ff
Stanford, Leland - Death of mother B 53
Stanford, Leland - Death of Grant 9 40649
Stanford, Leland - Death of Grant 20 40546
Stanford, Leland - Educational philosophy 25 28 ff
Stanford, Leland - Educational philosophy D 17
Stanford, Leland - Estate 3 82, 140
Stanford, Leland - Estate 4 39 ff
Stanford, Leland - Estate 5 27
Stanford, Leland - Estate 6 76
Stanford, Leland - Estate 9 128 ff
Stanford, Leland - Estate 23 13 ff
Stanford, Leland - Estate 24 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Estate 31 35, 36, 42
Stanford, Leland - Estate D 60, 66
Stanford, Leland - Family 10 28, 39, 60
Stanford, Leland - Family 31 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Family, Brothers B 52
Stanford, Leland - Funeral 3 141, 142
Stanford, Leland - Funeral 4 23 ff
Stanford, Leland - Funeral 5 4 ff
Stanford, Leland - Funeral D 14 ff
Stanford, Leland - Genealogy 11 41
Stanford, Leland - Gold Spike 3 140
Stanford, Leland - Gold Spike B 19 ff
Stanford, Leland - Governor 20 19
Stanford, Leland - Governor 26 1, 7, 42
Stanford, Leland - Governor B 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Governor C 3, 10
Stanford, Leland - Governor Stanford Locomotive B 86
Stanford, Leland - Health 3 85 ff
Stanford, Leland - Health 6 75 ff
Stanford, Leland - Health 17 34
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 1 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 2 23 ff
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 3 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 6 87
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 10 24 ff
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 11 51 ff
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 13 56
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 14 13 ff
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 17 14 ff
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 18 11 ff
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 21 51, 59
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 22 36161
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 25 3 ff
Stanford, Leland - Horse raising 28 97-99, 105
Stanford, Leland - Huntington episode 1 74 ff
Stanford, Leland - Huntington episode 2 123-125
Stanford, Leland - Muybridge experiments B 57
Stanford, Leland - Organizations, member of 20 18
Stanford, Leland - Palo Alto Stock Farm 2 45
Stanford, Leland - Palo Alto Stock Farm 3 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Palo Alto Stock Farm 6 87-89
Stanford, Leland - Palo Alto Stock Farm 17 61-62
Stanford, Leland - Palo Alto Stock Farm 31 37, 49
Stanford, Leland - Palo Alto Stock Farm B 66 ff
Stanford, Leland - Palo Alto Stock Farm Horses 6 43, 86-87
Stanford, Leland - Palo Alto Stock Farm Horses D 45 ff
Stanford, Leland - Politics, California B 16, 20
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1886 13 36
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1886 20 31, 33, 39
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1887 6 63 ff
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1887 14 10 ff
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1888 10 11 ff
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1888 11 43, 47
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1888 16 6 ff
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1888 18 18 ff
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1888 19 4 ff
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1892 1 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1892 2 2 ff
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1892 3 10 ff
Stanford, Leland - Presidential possibility 1892 17 76 ff
Stanford, Leland - Private railroad car B 86
Stanford, Leland - Reminiscences about D 56, 57
Stanford, Leland - Residences, Palo Alto 2 160
Stanford, Leland - Residences, Palo Alto 14 36
Stanford, Leland - Residences, Sacramento B 51, 53
Stanford, Leland - Residences, San Francisco 3 14, 69
Stanford, Leland - Residences, San Francisco 13 38
Stanford, Leland - Residences, San Francisco 14 73
Stanford, Leland - Residences, San Francisco 17 3
Stanford, Leland - Residences, San Francisco 31 54
Stanford, Leland - Residences, San Francisco B 83, 56-57
Stanford, Leland - Residences, San Francisco D 43, 50
Stanford, Leland - Residences, Washington, DC 3 36
Stanford, Leland - Residences, Washington, DC 17 98, 107
Stanford, Leland - Senator 1 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Senator 2 2 ff
Stanford, Leland - Senator 3 2 ff
Stanford, Leland - Senator 6 35 ff
Stanford, Leland - Senator 10 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Senator 11 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Senator 12 19 ff
Stanford, Leland - Senator 13 36-37
Stanford, Leland - Senator 14 4 ff
Stanford, Leland - Senator 16 2, 11,12
Stanford, Leland - Senator 17 21 ff
Stanford, Leland - Senator 18 10 ff
Stanford, Leland - Senator 19 4, 5
Stanford, Leland - Senator 20 31, 33, 34, 4?
Stanford, Leland - Senator 21 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Senator 25 3 ff
Stanford, Leland - Senator 31 34, 35
Stanford, Leland - Senator C 4 ff
Stanford, Leland - Social life 1 4 ff
Stanford, Leland - Social life 2 2 ff
Stanford, Leland - Social life 3 2 ff
Stanford, Leland - Social life 10 1, 4, 51
Stanford, Leland - Social life 18 6, 7
Stanford, Leland - Social life 20 36, 37
Stanford, Leland - Social life B 60-65
Stanford, Leland - Social philosophy B 54
Stanford, Leland - Southern Pacific 1871-1878 28 3-135
Stanford, Leland - Southern Pacific 1873 27 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Southern Pacific 1873-1875 7 10 ff
Stanford, Leland - Southern Pacific 1886-1893 10 5, 6, 18
Stanford, Leland - Southern Pacific 1887-1889 14 8, 51, 90
Stanford, Leland - Southern Pacific 1887-1891 1 30, 65-74
Stanford, Leland - Southern Pacific 1887-1891 17 8, 63-64, 69
Stanford, Leland - Southern Pacific 1890 21 3, 9
Stanford, Leland - Southern Pacific 1890-1891 2 110-115, 118
Stanford, Leland - Southern Pacific 1891 3 4 ff
Stanford, Leland - Southern Pacific 1893 D 19
Stanford, Leland - Statuary D 62
Stanford, Leland - Tribute 4 3, 8
Stanford, Leland - Tribute 5 2 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 1 5 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 2 46 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 3 4 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 6 42-44, 60-68, 77, 82, 86
Stanford, Leland - and the University 8 7, 18, 19
Stanford, Leland - and the University 9 21 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 10 14 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 11 45,48, 55
Stanford, Leland - and the University 13 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 14 25 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 17 35 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 18 36 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 21 8 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 23 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 25 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - and the University 31 17, 49
Stanford, Leland - and the University 0 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - address to University Bd of Trustees 9 16-20
Stanford, Leland - Vina Ranch 2 21 ff
Stanford, Leland - Vina Ranch 3 1 ff
Stanford, Leland - Vina Ranch 9 86 ff
Stanford, Leland - Vina Ranch 11 56
Stanford, Leland - Vina Ranch 17 34, 52, 97
Stanford, Leland - Vina Ranch 18 33, 60
Stanford, Leland - Vina Ranch 21 75
Stanford, Leland - Vina Ranch 25 8, 59
Stanford, Leland - Vina Ranch B 70-72
Stanford, Leland - Vina Ranch C 17, 18, 27
Stanford, Leland - Vina Ranch D 17, 72
Stanford, Leland - Will 3 142
Stanford, Leland - Will 4 90, 107-109
Stanford, Leland - Will 5 8, 10, 25, 27
Stanford, Leland - Will 9 138 ff
Stanford, Leland - Will 10 62, 63, 67
Stanford, Leland - Will 13 62
Stanford, Leland - Will 31 43
Stanford, Leland - Will D 16 ff
Stanford, Leland - Woman Suffrage 3 14
Stanford, Leland Jr. - Birth D 63
Stanford, Leland Jr. - Death 6 76, 82
Stanford, Leland Jr. - Death 8 2 ff
Stanford, Leland Jr. - Death 25 13
Stanford, Leland Jr. - Portrait B 55
Stanford, Leland Jr. - Tomb D 13
Stanford, Leland Jr. - Tribute 8 2, 8-10
Stanford, Philip Welton 31 16
Stanford, Thomas Welton 23 13
Stanford, Thomas Welton - Spiritualism 31 47
Stanford, Thomas Welton - Spiritualism 18 90-93
Stanford University - Plans for 6 60-62
Stanford University - Engineering, School of, History 3 3
Stanford University - women at 3 103
Stanford University - women at 25 59
Stanford University -- History.; Clippings.; Stanford University -- Construction; Horse breeders.; Stanford University -- Planning.; California -- Politics and government -- 1850-1950.; Stanford University -- Administration.; Stanford University -- Buildings.; Railroads -- United States -- History.; Transportation -- Railroads; Central Pacific Railroad Company; Railroads -- History; Politics; Central Pacific Railroad; Stanford, Jane Lathrop; Palo Alto Stock Farm (Stanford, Calif.); Stanford, Leland; Vina Ranch (Calif.); Southern Pacific Company; Stanford family.; Stanford, Leland; Stanford family.
- Scrapbooks
  - Railroad affairs, the Stock Farm, Stanford for President, opening of the university, trip to California, and political activity., 1887-1891; 01 (Box 1)
  - Railroad affairs, the Stock Farm, Stanford for President, opening of the university, trip to California, and political activity., 1890-1891; 02 (Box 2)
  - Leland Stanford, his horses, the Vina Ranch, U. S. Senate, the university, and Stanford's views on a variety of subjects., 1891-1893; 03 (Box 3)
  - Death of Leland Stanford., 1893; 04 (Box 4)
  - Death of Leland Stanford., 1893; 05 (Box 5)
  - Railroad, the university, and the personal affairs of the Stanfords., 1881-1887; 06 (Box 6)
  - Railroad., 1873-1875; 07 (Box 7)
  - Death of Leland Dewitt Stanford (Leland Stanford Jr.)., 1884; 08 (Box 8)
  - University, with some clippings on the Vina Ranch (p. 92, 209), 1885-1894; 09 (Box 9)
  - Leland Stanford's politics, horses, death, and will., 1886-1893; 10 (Box 10)
  - Leland Stanford's politics and his horses., 1885-1889; 11 (Box 11)
  - Railroad, Stanford's politics (pp. 19-26), biographical material (pp. 27-46), and nomination to the Senate., 1885; 12 (Box 12)
  - Construction of the university (pp. 1-33), politics, the railroad, and the death of Leland Stanford., 1882-1889; 13 (Box 13)
  - Railroad, Leland Stanford's politics, and horses., 1887-1889; 14 (Box 14)
  - [Original scrapbook missing from the collection.], 15 (Box 15)
  - Stanford's politics and the railroad., 1888; 16 (Box 16)
  - Politics, horses, and miscellany., 1887-1891; 17 (Box 17)
  - Politics and the railroad., 1885-1889; 18 (Box 18)
  - Politics and the railroad., 1888; 19 (Box 19)
  - The University and politics., 1885-1886; 20 (Box 20)
  - Politics, with some clippings on the university included, 1890; 21 (Box 21)
  - Horses, 1890-1892; 22 (Box 22)
  - Stanford University., 1894; 23 (Box 23)
  - Railroad., 1894; 24 (Box 24)
  - Railroad, politics and the University., 1889; 25 (Box 25)
  - Railroad., 1872; 26 (Box 26)
  - Railroad., 1873; 27 (Box 27)
  - Railroad., 1871-1878; 28 (Box 28)
  - Railroad., 1872; 29 (Box 29)
  - Railroad., 1872-1873; 30 (Box 30)
  - New York branch of the Stanford family, especially Welton Stanford and Grant L. Stanford., undated; 31 (Box 31)
  - Colored picture postcards collected by Jane Stanford on one of her European tours (not microfilmed)., 32 (Box 32)
  - Microfilm copies of scrapbooks, 7 microfilm reel(s) (Box 33)
  - Construction of the Central Pacific Railroad., 1865; A (Box A)
  - Politics (pp. 1-7), the railroad (pp. 8-50), miscellany, and horses (pp. 66-79)., 1861-1872; B (Box B)
  - Politics, as well as on other miscellaneous subjects., 1885-1888; C (Box C)
  - Death of Leland Stanford, Stanford University, and horses., 1893; D (Box D)
  - Vrooman Scrapbook: founding of Stanford University., 1885; V (Box V)